我认为你首先得通过非常诚实地
I think you go about reclaiming passion
了解你已经失去了
by first of all being very honest about
多少激情来重拾激情，
how much of it you've lost which means
这意味着你要愿意感受自己的痛苦。
the willingness to feel your own pain.
我曾经写过这样一个事实：
I've written about the fact that
在我自己的旅程中，
in my own journey I have suffered through
我经历了两次非常严重的临床抑郁症，
two very serious bouts of clinical depression
这是我失去激情的终极表现。
which is the ultimate in the loss of passion.
这是一种生命绝对死寂的状态，
It's a state of absolute deadness
在其中你根本无力感受到任何东西。
in which you're not capable of feeling anything at all.
在我们的社会中，
And we have in our society
我们有很多策略来控制这种状态，
so many strategies for holding that at bay
否认它的存在，
denying that it's going on or
或者干脆让你的生活堕落到
simply letting your life degenerate into
一种冰冷的玩世不恭的状态，
a kind of frozen cynical state,
或者也许给自己吃点药，
or perhaps medicating yourself,
有些抑郁症确实需要药物治疗，
some depressions do indeed need medication,
但我说的是一种抑郁症，
but I'm talking about a kind of depression where
药物治疗根本无效，开启内心旅程才有用。
medication is not the answer taking an inner journey is.
在这方面，我有一些个人经验，
So I have some personal experience that
首先是要说出你面对
difficulty of...,  first of all naming your pain
这个尴尬的事实所带来的痛苦。
of facing the awkward fact.
这个事实常常让你觉得自己是个失败者，
The fact that often makes you feel like a failure
我几乎被自己的绝望所麻痹，
that I am very nearly paralyzed by my own despair,
但事实证明，承认这一点
but that turns out the acknowledgement of that
可以给我们带来巨大的解放，
turns out to be an enormously liberating step
因为你开始承认在你的黑暗中
as you start to acknowledge your own pain
存在着痛苦，然后进入这种痛苦，
in your own darkness and move into it
而不是试图绕过它或者越过它。
rather than trying to get around it or go over it.
事实证明，在那种痛苦和绝望中，
It turns out that in that pain and despair are
有很多很多关于你的灵魂
lots and lots of clues about what your soul is
试图在你身上唤起什么的线索。
trying to call forth in you.
因此，我认为重拾激情的第一步是
So step one I think in reclaiming passion is
承认我不再拥有它，
just to acknowledge that I don't have it anymore,
我认为这可以建立起一种
that I think can set up a yearning for a memory
你曾拥有过的富足而充实人生记忆的向往。
that you have of when life was rich and full.
而且可以让你开始一个漫长的过程，
And can start you in on a long process
这个过程很难描述，
that's very hard to describe it and
当然也没有任何噱头或诀窍。
there certainly aren't any gimmicks or tricks about it.
这主要是通过你的记忆
It's mainly slogging in part back
进行部分回溯，
through your memory to reclaim,
首先是重拾回忆，然后重拾
to recall first and then reclaim the reasons
你为何想当老师
why you wanted to be a teacher
或为何想成为一个真正的人
or wanted to be a real person
或为何想在地球上
or wanted to feel alive and well
感到活出鲜活生命的理由。
on the face of the earth in the first place.
我认为...， 我不知道自己如何去做这件事。
And I think it..., I wouldn't know how to do that by myself.
它有一个孤独的层面，
And there is a solitary dimension to it
是任何人都无法避免的,
that no human being can avoid,
但不管怎样，我们必须找到社区的形式，
but somehow we have to find forms of community
帮助人们保持那份孤独，
that help people hold that solitude
尊敬和尊重那份孤独。
that honor and respect that solitude.
诗人里尔克曾经说过：
The poet Rilke once said,
“爱是两颗寂寞的心，
"Love is this the two solitudes border
相互保护，相互致敬”。
protect and salute one another".
对我来说，这一直是我心中
And for me that's always been a wonderful image
真正社区的一个美妙形象。
of what real community looks like.
社区不是一个要求
Community is not a place where it's demanded
我要振作起来，精神抖擞
that I be up and on and cheery and
并每时每刻为美好事物有所贡献的地方。
contributing to good at every moment, on everyday.
社区是这样一个地方，
Community is a place where
在那里，不管任何情况，我都会接纳，
I can be held in whatever condition I am,
而通过被接纳，我被赠予了空间和恩典，
and by being held I am given the space and the grace,
帮我找到那些可让我恢复活力的内在力量。
to find those inner resources that can bring me back to life.
我认为在教师培训项目中,
And I think in the teacher formation program,
我们正在努力创造这样的社区。
we're trying to create that kind of community.
我认为这是美国生活中一种罕见的社区形式。
I think it's a rare form of community in American life.
不是一个告诉你
Not a community that tells you
应该做什么或你应该是什么的社区。
what you ought to do or what you ought to be.
也不是一个你想说什么
And not a community in which
就说什么但没人倾听的社区。
you can say anything you want but nobody's listening.
而是一个参与的社区，
But rather a community of engagement
在那里你被接受为你自己，
where you are accepted as you are,
一个有着无条件的爱的社区。
a community of unconditional love.
我认为这就是我们需要的，以重拾我们的激情。
I think that's what we need to reclaim our passion.